<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bots on Rock Neurotiko&#39;s web &lt;3</title>
    <link>http://web.neurotiko.com/categories/bots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bots on Rock Neurotiko&#39;s web &lt;3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://web.neurotiko.com/categories/bots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentle introduction to Telegram Bots.</title>
      <link>http://web.neurotiko.com/blog/2015/07/21/gentle-introduction-to-telegram-bots./</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://web.neurotiko.com/blog/2015/07/21/gentle-introduction-to-telegram-bots./</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there, I don&amp;rsquo;t know who you are, so let&amp;rsquo;s start with a simple presentation, because this is my first post in my blog (yay! after 1 year ^^), and probably this is your first post reading here. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with the presentation, you can do the same in the comments section ^^.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;code&gt;Rock Neurotiko&lt;/code&gt;, 23 years old, Spanish and I&amp;rsquo;m studying Computer Engineering career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the career loving &lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt;, and hating &lt;code&gt;Java&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, four years after, I love many languages, the first ones that have comed to my mind are: &lt;code&gt;Scala&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Haskell&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;TypeScript&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Go&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Ponylang&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Elm&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Julia&lt;/code&gt;, &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt; has been relegated to a second place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still hate &lt;code&gt;Java&lt;/code&gt; but &lt;code&gt;Perl&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Ruby&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;PHP&lt;/code&gt; has joined to my hated languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But stop talking about me, let&amp;rsquo;s start talk about &lt;code&gt;Telegram&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Bots&lt;/code&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that is why you are here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://web.neurotiko.com/images/go-bots/simply-write.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;One does not simply write a Telegram Bot Meme&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, let&amp;rsquo;s see some &amp;ldquo;definitions&amp;rdquo; (by myself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Telegram&lt;/code&gt;: Telegram is an instant messaging system, multi-platform, focuses in security and privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bot&lt;/code&gt;: A bot it&amp;rsquo;s a computer program that perform some operations automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question could be: &amp;ldquo;Why a bot in Telegram?&amp;rdquo;. Well, the bots let you automate things and makes your life easier, for example, if you want to send an image to a friend, or search an image of something, instead of open a web-browser and search for an image, you can talk to a bot and tell him: &lt;code&gt;Image of &amp;lt;something&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, and he returns you an image of that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really simple bot, but can be as complex as you want, for example, a bot that connects with a programmable coffee pot and you set the time and type of coffee to make =D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The power of telegram is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have it only in your phone, you have it in your phone, in your computers, in your tablets, in every computer that you take. I use it every day, and I use the bots to help me in my day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In every instant messaging system that I know, the people always try to make bots, and Telegram is not an exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main communication with Telegram servers are with a binary protocol invented by them, it&amp;rsquo;s called MTProto, you can see &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/mtproto&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; the specification and all the links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you wanted to build a bot, you needed to communicate with the telegram servers using mtproto, and you had two options (as far as I know), do it manually in your language, or use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vysheng/tg/&#34;&gt;tg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;tg&lt;/code&gt; is a telegram terminal client for Unix systems (now they have compatibility with windows using cygwin), is writed in C, and the magic is that they have a library wrapper for Lua! What does it means? It means that you can program your bots using Lua, without worrying about mtproto!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, at the beginning (almost) all the bots were builted with &lt;code&gt;tg&lt;/code&gt; and Lua (they added support for Python and json output later).The most popular bot was (and maybe still are) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yagop/telegram-bot/&#34;&gt;telegram-bot&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yagop&#34;&gt;@yagop&lt;/a&gt;, telegram-bot is a multi-purpose bot based on plugins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can take a look at that project, it have so many plugins, and so good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to configure the bot in a real telegram account, with a phone number, and it looks like a normal user (actually you can log with the same number in another client and see all the messages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked pretty well, and it&amp;rsquo;s really powerful. Telegram saw it too, and they decided to create a Bot API so people can build the bots in their favourite language without using mtproto (and more improvements over traditional bots).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They released it in mid-june (if my memory don&amp;rsquo;t fail), and it was a really surprise, at least to the people in the telegram-bot development group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They opened the &lt;code&gt;Bot Revolution&lt;/code&gt; as they call it with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/blog/bot-revolution&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; and released some bots builted in the platform&amp;rsquo;s Beta (listed in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/blog/bot-revolution&#34;&gt;blog-post&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That post is really great, but don&amp;rsquo;t help too much to the developers, lucky of us they released two more pages, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/bots&#34;&gt;introduction for developers&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/bots/api&#34;&gt;API specification&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This too links are really needed to continue developing bots (knowing programming too!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to close this post here, with the homework of reading the &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/bots&#34;&gt;introduction for developers&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://core.telegram.org/bots/api&#34;&gt;API specification&lt;/a&gt; before the next post (I don&amp;rsquo;t know when will be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I almost forgot, you should start learning &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;, it will be the language that I will be using ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know some programming, you can see the video &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CF9S4QZuV30&#34;&gt;Learn Go in one video&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s really great explained!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know some programming&amp;hellip; well, I guess that you should search in google to llearn programming first ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers, and may the Bot be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>